

Sherif Barakat

18-years' Experience in programming, database, including 7 years working for an Oil & Gas industry. Wide technical knowledge in programming and data structure in different prospective. Solutions expert for Big Data projects, Business intelligence and Machine Learning. Also, expert in training methodologies and knowledge delivery.



Born: 28/12/1977Home Country: EgyptCountry of Residence: Malaysia

Cellphone: +60 176439060Languages: English, Arabic

E-Mail : sherifmagdy2007@yahoo.com

Education

- Master degree in science of computing (Staffordshire University- APIIT- Malaysia) -June/2013.
- Postgraduate Diploma in Computing (Staffordshire University- APIIT- Malaysia) -November/2012.
- Certificate in Computing (Staffordshire University- APIIT- Malaysia) May/2012.
- BCs. Agriculture from Cairo University (Botany and Genetics)- January/2002

Publications

- Journal of Education and Vocational Research
- Vol. 4, No. 3, pp. 60-68, Mar 2013 (ISSN 2221-2590)
- Title: Enhanced UML Methodology with New Hybrid Diagrams: An ATM Application

Certificates

- (MCSE) Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert (2015)
- (MCSA) Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate (2014)
- (MCP) Microsoft Certified Professional (2005)
- (MCT) Microsoft Certified Trainer (2017)

Skills Profile

- Programming C++, C#, Java, Python.
- Python programming (Developing and Data analysis).
- ASP.net MVC Core 3 (C#, HTML 5, CSS 3, Java script).
- Database MSSQL (Querying, data warehouse, encryption, SSIS, administration, development, high availability and performance Tuning).
- Design and implementation of ETL and big data project.
- Database Oracle (Querying, Administration and Data Warehouse).
- Database MYSQL (Querying, Administration, and Development).
- IBM DB2 database.
- Mongo DB.
- Analyzing Data with Power BI.
- Automotive administration with PowerShell.



Recent Working Experience

August 2017 – Up to date Microsoft Certified Trainer

(Programming &Databases)

November 2016 – August 2017 Computer Science Lecturer

Thebes Academy-Egypt

September 2015 – October 2016 Data Structure & Programming Trainer

Alex Library – Cairo Branch

December 2013 – July 2015 IT programmer information system and technology

Bumi Armada Berhad - Malaysia

September 2008 – August 2013 IT Specialist & Data Controller

Asian Geos Sdn Bhd - Malaysia

PREVIOUS RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

- Computer crime & advanced networking instructor in Ministry of Interior-Egypt (2005-2008-Full time).
- Trainer ICDL and Networks at ICI-Egypt (2005-2008-Part time).
- Installation and Maintenance Manager in Misria for computer systems -Egypt (2004-2005).
- Power House for generators as a IT technical support-Egypt (2003 2004).
- Modern Educational School as a technical support-Egypt (2002 2003).
- Morocco Embassy in Cairo as a technical support-Egypt (2002 2003).
- Trainer in Russian Culture Center-Egypt (2002 2003-Part time).
- Network Administrator and technical support at Diabetes Institute -Egypt (2000-2002 -Full Time).

Language Skills

- Arabic Mother language
- English Fluent
- French Intermediate

Hobbies

- Reading.
- Travelling.
- Gym

Availability

• To be agreed, but could be short.